Michael Milroy



I am a Marine Corps Veteran with unique experience in signals intelligence analysis and network security. I am always learning more in software development, data analytics, and Agile methodologies. Currently part of a team that is leading process improvement based on Lean, Agile, and Scrum practices within State Government.

Software Developer Lafayette, IN

C: (765) 977-6349 E: michaeldmilroy@gmail.com

Work Experience

Indiana Bureau of Motor Vehicles, Intake Lead, Jul 2019 - Present

Lead and coached process improvement through Lean, Agile, and Scrum practices. Co-led the agency's Scaled Agile transformation comprised of 120 practitioners. Currently coaching business teams on the use of Agile Software Development practices. My team is responsible for the maturity of the agency's Agile expertise and reducing variation in processes across the agency.

Indiana Bureau of Motor Vehicles, Project Manager, Jan 2019 – Jul 2019

Traditional Project Manager leading projects through Project Management Institute's PMBOK practices and methodologies. Led a Six Sigma project as the Black Belt that reduced variation in the output of the agency's development teams by over 60%.

United States Marine Corps, Signals Intelligence Operator/Analyst, Jun 2010 – Jun 2015

Subject matter expert in the field of signals intelligence collection and analysis. Experience in computer network security-defense and exploitation, electromagnetic spectrum, geo-location, and various communication network typologies.

Education

Eleven Fifty Academy, Other, **Software Development**, Feb 2020 – July 2020

Learning C# development within the .NET framework. I have created console applications, data repositories, worked via pair-programming, and currently working through Web APIs, all including daily interaction with Git (bash) and Github. Created several projects in HTML/CSS such as static websites and portfolios.

Data Camp, Non-Degree Program, Data Analyst, 2018

Data analytics with intermediate and advanced python tools, techniques, and libraries.

Purdue University, Bachelor of Science (BS), Psychology, Aug 2017 – Dec 2018

Focus on organizational psychology with an emphasis on behavioral and statistical practices.

Certifications

SAFe Program Consultant (SPC 5) - expires Jan 2021

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) - expires May 2021

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM) - expires Sep 2024

Certified Six Sigma Blackbelt (Purdue MEP) - no expiration